Wanqiu Raymer

Troy | +5175809836 | yanwanqiu@gmail.com

Highly knowledgeable certified bilingual educator with 10+ years of experience. Provides excellent interpersonal skills and a strong ability to work with individuals one-on-one or in large group settings. Displays excellent collaboration with members of the leadership team. Motivated achiever, dedicated to excellence in service and building relationships. Provides a strong background in planning, facilitating, supporting, and assessing learning to reach organizational outcomes.

Certification

State of Michigan Professional Teaching Certificate

Chinese (mandarin) (FR) K-12 Endorsement

Professional Experience

Oakland ISD | Waterford, MI

Curriculum Development Specialist | September 2021 - Present

- Exceed expectations in all work responsibilities through maximizing resources and providing assistance to two teachers throughout employment
- Integrate technology into the curriculum and design activities to promote student engagement
- Adapt to a constantly changing and dynamic environment to best support student engagement and learning goals
- Exemplify flexibility by adapting to a constantly changing and dynamic environment while overseeing the lesson plan and development of students throughout the county

Notre Dame Preparatory School and Marist Academy | Pontiac, MI Secondary Chinese Teacher | August 2018 - Present

- Instruct Chinese language and culture to 6-10 grade students in the middle school and high school
- Design four-level lessons daily according to students' language proficiency
- Incorporate constructive feedback from three supervisors to reduce process inefficiencies, ensure accuracy, and allow for professional development
- Assist teachers, and curriculum writers by participating and sharing responsibility in the world language department
- Rated highly effective for the past three consecutive years

Oxford Community Schools | Oxford, MI Secondary Chinese Teacher | September 2016 - June 2018

- Developed an introductory Chinese curriculum with three other Chinese teachers at the middle school, then presented it to the school board for review
- Produced student assessments that meet IB standards, providing meticulous attention to detail to produce accurate records
- Responded to questions and concerns from parents, supervisors, and coworkers in a timely and respectable fashion
- Managed 80-100 students' personal files; updating records as needed based on attendance, learning, absences, and personal information

Utica Community Schools | Sterling Heights, MI Elementary School Chinese Teacher | September 2015 - June 2016

- Created a presentation for 20-30 staff members to introduce Chinese culture and cultural awareness to school employees
- Initiated the curriculum development effort for the Chinese language and culture program while switching from the immersion program
- Maintained a personable, friendly, and caring attitude while identifying students' needs and creating an individualized plan catered to each person's abilities

 Exceeded expectations in all work responsibilities through maximizing resources and providing assistance to 120 students throughout education

Warren Woods Public Schools | Warren, MI Elementary School Chinese Teacher | September 2012 - June 2015

- Taught Chinese language and culture programs to 800 students (Grades k-5) utilizing small and large group activities that engaged students and enhanced learning
- Attended district-wide and county-wide conferences, New Teacher Academy, and seminars to remain current on instruction methods and improve overall day-to-day teaching
- Promoted student self-confidence by displaying their work throughout the school and organizing family engagement events to establish communication with parents and the community

Additional Experience

Beishan High School | High School English Teacher, University of Hawaii | Startalk Summer Chinese Program, Michigan State University | Startalk Summer Chinese Program, BCC International Education Group| Curriculum Development Workshop

Core Competencies

Student Evaluation, Research, Curriculum Design, Written and Verbal Communication, Detail-Oriented, Organization, Self-Motivation, Teaching, Relationship Development, Continuing Education, Time Management, Positivity, Computer Knowledge, Leadership, Precision, Accuracy, Active Listening, Empathy, Compliance, Multitasking, Professionalism

Education

Educational Specialist in LearningTechnology, University of Missouri Master of Arts in Teaching and Curriculum, Michigan State University Master of Arts in English, Renmin University of China Bachelor of Arts in English, Southwest University

Awards

Excellent New Teacher Award, 2008
Excellent Student-Teacher, 2006
Excellent Individual for Social Practice, 2006- 2007
Excellent Individual for Teaching Practice, 2005 - 2006
First-Class Scholarship RUC
Second-Class Scholarship to RUC
Third-Class Scholarship of SWU